# Adithya Ajith Software Developer

Address: 1435 Woodbine Avenue, Toronto, ON M4C4G8

Mobile: 4372217180

Email: ajithadithya38@gmail.com

## **Summary:**

Experienced Software Engineering professional with a bachelor's degree in computer science from India's top engineering school and a post-graduation degree in big data architecture and software testing in Canada. I acquired a strong knowledge of full-stack development during my two-year work term in fast-paced startup environments. I'm well capable of working under pressure, learning new technologies, team management, problem-solving, and possess good communication skills.

#### **Skills and Abilities:**

**Programming**: Java, Python, C.

Web Technologies: JavaScript, Typescript, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Web services (REST),

AWS.

Frameworks: Angular, Ionic.

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows.

**Testing Frameworks:** JUnit, Pytest, Selenium.

Database: MYSQL, Mongo DB.

**IDE**: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Spyder.

## **Experience:**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, FIWE, KERALA INDIA

#### FROM JANUARY 2020 to March 2021

Developed android and IOS apps using Ionic 5 and Angular 9.

Experienced with angular modules, services, templates, directives, services and dependency injection to create a SPA.

Implemented REST APIs using Java Spring boot.

Used JSON Web Tokens for authentication.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, IPRIMED EDUCATION SOLUTIONS, BANGALORE INDIA

FROM JUNE 2018 TO APRIL 2019

Worked on both frontend and backend development to build an e-learning platform.

Implemented mobile application using Ionic.

Used Angular 5 to develop Single Page web applications.

Supported multiple projects simultaneously, troubleshooting and debugging.

#### **Education:**

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA, BIG DATA SOLUTIONS ARCHITECTURE, CONESTOGA COLLEGE, WATERLOO, ONTARIO FROM MAY 2020 TO DECEMBER 2020

Completed courses in Python, R for Data Analysis, Sql and NoSql programming, Hadoop for Big Data.

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA, SOFTWARE AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS TESTING, FANSHAWE COLLEGE, LONDON, ONTARIO

FROM MAY 2019 TO DECEMBER 2019

Completed courses in Java for development project management, Systems design and analysis, test automation, and Security screening.

BACHELOR'S DEGREE, COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, KERALA, INDIA

FROM AUGUST 2014 TO APRIL 2018

Acquired thorough knowledge in Object Oriented Programming, Web development, Software engineering, Data structures and algorithms, and Data mining.

## **Volunteer Experience:**

PEER TUTOR, FANSHAWE COLLEGE, LONDON ONTARIO FROM SEPTEMBER 2019 TO MARCH 2020

Helping students with doubts in Java.

One on one assistance to students for exams, projects and other course works.

U&I Trust, Calicut, Kerala

FROM AUGUST 2017 TO APRIL 2018

Took remedial lessons for high school students in Physics and Mathematics.

Helped them clear their doubts, assist them for completing their homework and guidance for their future.

#### Certification:

MACHINE LEARNING A-ZTM HANDS ON PYTHON AND R IN DATA SCIENCE FROM UDEMY ACADEMY CERTIFIED ON JULY 2018